{
    "id": "03e0ee5502ce4e629658e711f14d86a3",
    "title": "Comparatives and Superlatives",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The coat was ......................... than I thought.",
            "description": "We use the comparative form of the adjective before than.",
            "answers": [
                "more expensive",
                "most expensive",
                "the most expensive",
                "the more expensive"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "17acffd33a8c459894d9ea9af8bd5f2a"
        },
        {
            "question": "Canada is ......................... India.",
            "description": "Adjectives of one or two syllables form their comparative forms by adding -er to the positive adjective. ",
            "answers": [
                "bigger then",
                "bigger than",
                "more big than"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f51188f3cb05430e993efb6fa40b5509"
        },
        {
            "question": "He is not ................................. his brother.",
            "description": "When we make comparisons using the positive adjective, we use the structure as...as...",
            "answers": [
                "as successful as",
                "more successful as",
                "as successful than"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "8a2ecfcba96742c5baef29799b3e6887"
        },
        {
            "question": "Greenland is ......................... island in the world.",
            "description": "The superlative adjective is used when we compare one thing with the group to which it belongs. ",
            "answers": [
                "largest",
                "the largest",
                "larger",
                "the larger"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d1218978950441808b5bcb5b77781fe3"
        },
        {
            "question": "You are ............................... person I have met.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "most interesting",
                "the most interesting",
                "the more interesting"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3e991f68a6fa4bbf945344660c36a515"
        },
        {
            "question": "This is ............................ film I have ever watched.",
            "description": "Here we are comparing one film with all the films, and therefore a superlative adjective is used. ",
            "answers": [
                "best",
                "the best",
                "better",
                "the better"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ebfe89191e57425789deda391c35b1c4"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am not very hungry so I will give you the ....................... steak.",
            "description": "When a group has only two members, we can use either the comparative or the superlative however, the comparative is considered more appropriate here. ",
            "answers": [
                "bigger",
                "biggest",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3b9f5801e3284ba38645c42dd50ea154"
        },
        {
            "question": "This is ........................... carpet I have seen.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "dirtiest",
                "the dirtiest",
                "dirtyest"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c40c540373fc439783d865e01eba0883"
        },
        {
            "question": "She solved the puzzle ............................. than everybody else.",
            "description": "Either quicker or more quickly is possible here. ",
            "answers": [
                "quickly",
                "quicker",
                "more quickly",
                "more quicker"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "045c47b6a51545da9d6462714a45bc8d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I would be ............................ if I had more chin.",
            "description": "Some compound adjectives like good-looking have two possible comparatives. ",
            "answers": [
                "more good-looking",
                "better-looking",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "7250e9596dbe4ed68409299d7b548550"
        },
        {
            "question": "Thank you very much. That was ........................... of you.",
            "description": "Most can be used with adjectives to mean 'very'. So the sentence 'That was most kind of you' means 'That was very kind of you'.",
            "answers": [
                "most kind",
                "the kindest",
                "kinder",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "760243c7d59a4a07b7874d50217d1776"
        },
        {
            "question": "You are .......................... your mother than your father.",
            "description": "'Like' always has more and most. ",
            "answers": [
                "more like",
                "liker",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "07da58266020432cac7803a4d37be29e"
        }
    ]
}